Kevin Hayes Anderson

Chennai, India | +91 9585625041 | kevinhayesanderson@gmail.com | kevinhayesanderson.github.io

Professional Summary:

Senior software and cloud engineer with 7+ years of experience in Agile enterprise software development, cloud architecture, microservices and development in 6+ languages. Proficient in functional, low-level programming and Microsoft Azure Cloud Services. Interested in working with microservices using Rust.

Work History:

Ambigai Consultancy Services India Private Limited, Chennai, India

Dec 2019 - Present

Role: Software Development Lead

Client: Schaeffler | Domain: R&D Analysis Tools

- Developed Windows and Web pre- and post-processing applications for finite element analysis.
- Implemented and optimized core cloud-based calculation libraries for complex computations.
- Created and deployed a high-performance gRPC web service for License Management.
- Engineered a custom Native hosting suite from scratch for, seamlessly invoking functions in native processes.
- Enhanced performance of Web services, Windows apps, and cloud calculation libraries by optimizing codebases.
- Led and trained a team of two developers, collaborating closely with stakeholders to gather requirements and deliver solutions.

Tech Stack: .NET, Angular, ASP.NET Core, WPF, Functional Programming, Azure & Azure DevOps.

Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

Role: Full Stack Developer Client: H&M | Domain: Retail

- Implemented and optimized Web services to bolster domain services for microservice architecture.
- Created a test automation suite from the ground up using Selenium for regression testing.
- Developed and supervised the implementation of web applications using ASP.NET and Angular.

Client: Cigna | Domain: Healthcare

- Migrated legacy Visual Basic to WPF applications, enhancing user experience, and reducing load times.
- Directed the development and upkeep of backend web services for healthcare systems, implementing security protocols and enhancing interoperability with third-party systems.
- Improved the performance of batch processing background services by implementing parallel processing.

Tech Stack: .NET, Angular, ASP.NET, WPF, REST APIs, MVC, Microservices, SignalR and RabbitMQ.

Education:

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering, 8.1/10, Sastra University, India

Jan 2012 - Dec 2016

Skills:

Frameworks: .NET, Angular v16.

Languages: C#, F#, Rust, Typescript, Python, JavaScript, SQL.

Cloud, DevOps & Others: Azure, Git, Docker, SQL Server, Selenium.

Certifications:

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate. Credential link.

Cloud Developer using Microsoft Azure. Credential link.

IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer. Credential link.

Microsoft Technology Associate. Credential link. Code: nSE6-XVNa

And more...